[
    {
        "front": "How does quantum computing (QC) fit alongside classical high-performance computing (HPC) systems & applications?",
        "back": "QC will serve as an accelerator in HPC for specific parts of an application, leading to hybrid HPC-QC systems & applications."
    },
    {
        "front": "What type of sectors and computational problems does classical high-performance computing (HPC) enable?",
        "back": "Discuss across material science, engineering and manufacturing, molecular modelling, life science, fin tech, data analytics, machine learning, optimisation, logistics, modelling and simulation in fundamental sciences."
    },
    {
        "front": "If you were/need to gain access to quantum computers, then would you want on-premise or remote cloud access? Why?",
        "back": "Review your value proposition in quantum computing to identify your role (technology co-developer, service provider, user), security/strategy requirements, etc.. Also, consider your  software stack for your access mechanism."
    },
    {
        "front": "What is the nature and what are some examples of BQP class problems?",
        "back": "A bounded-error quantum polynomial time problem denotes one that is solvable by a quantum computer in polynomial time, with an error probability of at most 1/4 for all instances. Refer and discuss further details https://www.quantiki.org/wiki/bqp."
    },
    {
        "front": "What types of problems can quantum computing (QC) solve better than classical high-performance computing (HPC)?",
        "back": "Problems with approximations to address intractability, reducing precision when scaling complexity, simulate models which are related to quantum mechanics, etc.."
    },
    {
        "front": "How would you define your role & value in quantum computing (QC)?",
        "back": "This is best defined in discussion with experts in quantum computing systems & applications. Opportunities lie in end-user applications, co-development of technologies, ecosystem leadership, skills & training, etc.."
    },
    {
        "front": "What are key tipping points or milestones for quantum computing (QC) to become more reliable & scalable?",
        "back": "Improved noise & reliability in qubits & quantum gates, precision in control & engineering of quantum systems, integration of classical HPC & QC systems, higher-level software tools integrated with classical software tools."
    },
    {
        "front": "Do quantum computers always need to be refridgerated and operated at extremely low temperatures?",
        "back": "Not all quantum computer realisation methods require refridgeration and operation at extremely low temperatures. For instance, the superconducting approach requires refridgeration, while photonics or diamond-based approaches may be operated at room temperature."
    },
    {
        "front": "If real NISQ devices are already available for free access, then do we need software-based simulators of quantum computers?",
        "back": "Given the limitations of small and error-prone NISQ devices, software-based quantum simulators offer a valuable alternative for easier experimentation and skills development before transitioning to real hardware. Starting with simulators facilitates learning and development, providing a more accessible entry point compared to directly working with NISQ hardware."
    },
    {
        "front": "How or where can you start your engagement with quantum computing?",
        "back": "Investigate potential use-cases of interest, mechanisms for skills development, partners for collaborations & discussion, national & international programmes in which to participate, etc.."
    },
    {
        "front": "What are some mechanisms through which I can get access to quantum computing environments now?",
        "back": "There are a variety of free, open as well as paid, closed resources and support available. These are at national, European and global levels. Discuss with the ICHEC tutors to identify what suits your requirements."
    }    
]
